<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on SOCIAL GRAPHS BLOG</title>
    <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on SOCIAL GRAPHS BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A. Blair Waldorf</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/blair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/blair/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Blair waldorf or &amp;ldquo;Queen B&amp;rdquo;. Blair has an ongoing up and down relationship with Chuck Bass, and after Serena van der Woodsen and Dan Humphrey. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.
Blairs relations   This is the network of Blair. She has 64 number of relationships. As you can se, there are not 64 edges in the graph above, but she has several relationship types with the same people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B. Chuck Bass</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/chuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/chuck/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Chuck Bass. Throughout the television series, Chuck has an on-again/off-again relationship with Blair Waldorf. They marry in the series finale. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.
Chucks relations   This is the network of Chuck. He has 54 number of relationships. As you can se, there are not 54 edges in the graph above, but he has several relationship types with the same people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C. Dan Humphrey</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/dan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/dan/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Dan Humphrey or &amp;ldquo;Lonley Boy&amp;rdquo;. Dan has an on-again-off-again relationship with Serena van der Woodsen and the two have the longest running relationship on the show. Dan and Serena finally get married in the finale. Dan is good friends with Nate Archibald, Blair Waldorf, and Chuck Bass. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D. Eric Van Der Woodsen</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/eric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/eric/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Eric Van Der Woodsen. Eric is the brother of Serena van der Woodsen and son of Lily and William van der Woodsen. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.
Erics relations   This is the network of Eric. He has 33 number of relationships. As you can se, there are not 33 edges in the graph above, but he has several relationship types with the same people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E. Jenny Humphrey</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/jenny/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/jenny/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Jenny Humphrey. She is the younger sister of Dan Humphrey and a social climber who idolizes Blair Waldorf and Serena van der Woodsen. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.
Jennys relations   This is the network of Jenny. She has 39 number of relationships. As you can se, there are not 39 edges in the graph above, but she has several relationship types with the same people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F. Lily Van Der Woodsen</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/lily/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/lily/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Lily Van Der Woodsen. Lily is the mother to Serena and Eric van der Woodsen, as well as being the birth mother of Scott Rosson and the adoptive mother to Chuck Bass. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.
Lilys relations   This is the network of Lily. She has 44 number of relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G. Nate Archibald</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/nate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/nate/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Nate Archibald. Nate is best friends with Chuck Bass and is good friends with Dan Humphrey, Serena van der Woodsen and Blair Waldorf. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.
Nates relations   This is the network of Nate. He has 44 number of relationships. As you can se, there are not 44 edges in the graph above, but he has several relationship types with the same people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H. Serena Van Der Woodsen</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/serena/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/serena/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Serena Van Der Woodsen, or New Yorks It-girl. Serena has an on-again, off-again relationship with Dan Humphrey and the two have the longest running relationship on the show. She is best friends with Blair Waldorf and shares close friendships with Nate Archibald and Chuck Bass. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I. Rufus Humphrey</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/rufus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/rufus/</guid>
      <description>Here you can take a look at Rufus Humphrey. Rufus is the father of Dan and Jenny Humphrey, and the ex-husband of Alison Humphrey and Lily van der Woodsen. To take a closer look at the relations, we have made a graph and a wordcloud that visualizes them.
Rufus relations   This is the network of Rufus. He has 25 number of relationships. As you can se, there are not 25 edges in the graph above, but he has several relationship types with the same people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J. Henry Bass</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/henry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/characters/henry/</guid>
      <description>Henry Bass is the son of Chuck Bass and Blair Waldorf. Many may wonder why he is one of the Top 10 characters. But this is a perfect example of &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t hide from the past&amp;rdquo;. All of the relations and drama that has happend, has brought little Henry to life, but in to the drama and connected him to it.
Henrys relations   This is the network of Henry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K. The Dataset</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/data/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/data/data/</guid>
      <description>Data and basic stats  Data cleaning and preprocessing has ben used to fetch:  List of charachters The chrachters relatioships  The gender of the charachters  The Description of the charachter  
The data has been fetched to be used for Network analasys and text analasys.
Data Cleaning and preprosseding  To prosses and clean data the very popular Pytonlibrary Beautiful Soup has been used. Al data has been fetched by using the html tag and a unique identifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L. The Families</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/family/family/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/family/family/</guid>
      <description>In gossip Girl, there are alot of family drama and intrigues. The drama is about power, money and romantic relationships. The family drama has left us wondering, which of these families are actually the most powerful? We have therefore chosen to analyze this. We want to see which family is the most powerful, and which has the most contacts. The result is visualized in a network that shows amount of relations the three families have with the characters in gossip girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M. Networking</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/network/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/network/network/</guid>
      <description>The Whole Network   We have analyzed the episodes and seasons and the characters impact on them. The Graph shows the relations between all the characters ever participateed in the Gossip Girl series. The nodes are the characters, and they are also defined with their charater name. The edge between to nodes define that they have a relation, and the color of the edge define what type of relation. If the edge is grey, they are in family with each other, if it is pink they have a romantic relationship, if it is blue they are friends and if it is purple, they are enemies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N. Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/sentiment/sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/sentiment/sentiment/</guid>
      <description> Sentiment Analysis      Sentiment Analysis      Sentiment Analysis      Sentiment Analysis     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O. Team</title>
      <link>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/team/team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elisealm.github.io/socialgraphsblog.github.io/posts/team/team/</guid>
      <description>Oline Zachariassen  MSc Computer Science  
Elise Almestad  MSc Computer Science</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
